A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 1, Accession 2017:057 FA1317
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 1, Accession 2017:057
1966-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation
FA1317
35.13 Cubic Feet 94 boxes: 93 letter-sized document boxes, 1 half letter-size document box.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Henry Luce Foundation in 2017.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Henry Luce Foundation was established by Henry R. Luce in 1936. As a New York-based nonprofit organization, the Luce Foundation awards grants in American Art, Asian studies, Higher Education, Theology, and supports the Clare Boothe Luce Program for women in science, mathematics, and engineering.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Luce Foundation records (Record Group 1) contain project files, most of which are related to the American Art program.
Arrangement
The Henry Luce Foundation records (Record Group 1) are arranged as follows:
Series 1: Awards, 1982-1991
Series 2: Grants, 1967-1991
Series 3: Project Files, 1966-1999
Series 4: Scholarships in American Art, 1982-1993
Related Materials
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 2, Accession 2017:058 (FA1393)
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 3, Accession 2017:059 (FA1410)
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 4, Accession 2017:060 (FA1442)
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 5, Accession 2017:061 (FA1472)
Art, American; International economic relations -- Study and teaching -- Asia, Southeastern; Education (Higher); Religion; Theology
- Awards, 1982-1991; 1
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery - Abstract Expressionism, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amon Carter Museum - Gilpin, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Amon Carter Museum - Western Narrative, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art Institute of Chicago - Hilberseimer, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art - 20th Century American Paintings, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art - American Furniture, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art - Benjamin West, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Berkeley University Art Museum, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts - Arts and Crafts Movement, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts - The Boston School, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts - Charles Sheeler, 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn Museum - Ruskin, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Institute - John LaFarge, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie Museum of Art, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Museum of Art - Landscape Video Project, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum - Creative Spark, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Columbus Museum of Art - American Art Collection, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Columbus Museum of Art - American Art (past decade), 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art - American Landscape, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts - Bybee Collection, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts - Pre-WWII American Paintings, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Denver Art Museum - Childe Hassam, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Denver Art Museum - H. Bayer Archive, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Denver Art Museum - Native American Art, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco - American Artists in Venice, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco - Catalog of American Paintings, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco - Winslow Homer, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
  - Fogg Art Museum, 1982-1990 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Hudson River Museum - American Women Sculptors, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - The Hudson River Museum - Women Sculptors, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - The Hudson River Museum - The Catskills: Above the Clouds, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - The Hudson River Museum - The Natural Sublime, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art - George Innes, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute - Key Works, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Museum of Modern Art - American Prints, 1982-1988 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Rhode Island School of Design (RISD), 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Rhode Island School of Design (RISD) - American Decorative Art, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Rhode Island School of Design (RISD) - Rhode Island Landscape, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Phillips Collection, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Phillips Collection - Research and Catalog, 1983-1989 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts - Catalog of American Paintings, 1983-1989 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts - Thomas Eakins, 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art - Figurative Tradition, 1983-1989 (Box 7, Folder 52-53)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art - Surrealism, 1982-1988 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Seattle Art Museum - Art of the Pacific North W, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 55-56)
  - St. Louis Art Museum, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - St. Louis Art Museum - Frederic Remington, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - St. Louis Art Museum - Louis Sullivan (Architecture), 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Walker Art Center, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Walker Art Center - Catalog of American Art Collection, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Walker Art Center - Tyler Graphics, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art - C. Demuth, 1983-1989 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1982-1989 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum - Archives and Museum History, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Worchester Art Museum, 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 66-67)
  - Yale University Art Gallery - At Home in Manhattan, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Yale University Art Gallery - Case Furniture, 1983-1988 (Box 9, Folder 69)
- Grants, 1967-1991; 2
  - American Association of College Registrars and Admissions Officers, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - American Bar Association, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1978-1983 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - The American Studies Institute, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Asia Foundation, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - The Asia Society - China Council (Renewal Request), 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Asian-American Assembly for Policy Research, 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Asian-American Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Association of Theological Schools in the U.S. and Canada, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Colgate Rochester Divinity School, 1978-1982 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - College of Wooster (Garber Drushal), 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Colorado College, 1978-1982 (Box 10, Folder 81-82)
  - Columbia University - Teacher's College, 1978-1987 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Columbia University - School of Business, 1977-1984 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Connecticut College, 1977-1988 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Economic Development Council, 1978-1983 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Graduate Theological Union - Center for the Study of American Religious Movements, 1977-1981 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Indiana University, 1983-1991 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Institutes of Religion and Health, 1986-1990 (Box 11, Folder 90-91)
  - International Federation for Modern Language and Literature, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - International Foundation for Art Research (IFAR), 1986-1990 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - International Institute of Rural Reconstruction, 1984-1989 (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Interdenominational Theological Center, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - Institute of International Education, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Japan Society, 1986-1991 (Box 12, Folder 97-98)
  - Japan Society - Symposium re Statistical Research of Nihonjin Kenkyukai, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Johns Hopkins - School of Advanced International Studies (Ralph Clough), 1982-1987 (Box 13, Folder 100-101)
  - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 102)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1976-1988 (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - Meharry Medical College, 1978-1984 (Box 13, Folder 104)
  - Mexican-American Legal Defense Education Fund, 1978-1986 (Box 13, Folder 105)
  - Mexican-American League Defense Fund, 1973-1988 (Box 13, Folder 106)
  - Michigan State University, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 107)
  - Morehouse School of Medicine, 1984-1992 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - National Academy of Design, 1985-1993 (Box 14, Folder 109)
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 1984-1990 (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1983-1987 (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - National Association of Independent Schools, 1985-1989 (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations, 1977-1989 (Box 14, Folder 113-114)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1984-1990 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - National Council of La Raza, 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - National Council of Negro Women, Inc., 1978-1981 (Box 15, Folder 117)
  - National Council on Foreign Language and International Studies, 1980-1988 (Box 15, Folder 118)
  - National Executive Service Corps., 1984-1989 (Box 15, Folder 119-120)
  - National Fund for Minority Engineering Studies, 1977-1982 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - National Museum of American Art, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - National Museum of American Art - Inventory of American Sculpture, 1986-1992 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - National Network of Runaway and Youth Services, 1978-1983 (Box 16, Folder 124)
  - National Urban League, 1984-1989 (Box 16, Folder 125)
  - National Urban League - Economist, 1978-1983 (Box 16, Folder 126)
  - National Urban League - Management Training and Development Program, National Conference, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 127)
  - National Theatre of the Deaf, 1984-1987 (Box 16, Folder 128-129)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1986-1991 (Box 16, Folder 130)
  - Nelson-Atkins Museum, 1986-1993 (Box 17, Folder 131-132)
  - The New Museum of Contemporary Art, 1985-1991 (Box 17, Folder 133)
  - New York University - Institute of the Fine Arts, 1984-1991 (Box 17, Folder 134)
  - Newark Museum - Against All Odds, 1986-1991 (Box 17, Folder 135)
  - Our Lady of Melpkin Abbey, 1967-1987 (Box 17, Folder 136)
  - Overseas Development Council, 1977-1979 (Box 18, Folder 137)
  - Partners for Livable Places, 1981-1987 (Box 18, Folder 138)
  - The Pierpont Morgan Library, 1977-1986 (Box 18, Folder 139)
  - Princeton Theological Seminary, 1983-1987 (Box 18, Folder 140)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1982-1986 (Box 18, Folder 141-142)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1983-1986 (Box 18, Folder 143)
  - Society for International Development, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 144)
  - Southeast Asian Ministries of Education Secretariat (SEAMES), 1977-1985 (Box 19, Folder 145)
  - Spelman College, 1979-1983 (Box 19, Folder 146)
  - Stanford University - Human Nutrition Program, 1976-1987 (Box 19, Folder 147)
  - Support Centers of America, 1982-1987 (Box 19, Folder 148)
  - Union Theological Seminary, 1978-1983 (Box 19, Folder 149)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia - Sataya Wacana, 1983-1985 (Box 19, Folder 150)
  - United Methodist Reporter - Religious News Service, 1983-1985 (Box 19, Folder 151)
  - University of Maryland Libraries - Asia and China, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 152)
  - United Nations Association, 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 153)
  - United Nations University, 1978-1985 (Box 20, Folder 154)
  - United Negro College Fund, 1977-1981 (Box 20, Folder 155)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 1978-1986 (Box 20, Folder 156)
  - Williams College (Renewal), 1982-1985 (Box 20, Folder 157)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center, 1979-1987 (Box 20, Folder 158-159)
  - Yale-China Association, 1982-1985 (Box 21, Folder 162)
  - Yale University - Council on Southeast Asia Studies, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 163)
  - Yale University - Divinity School, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 164)
  - Yale University - Whitney Humanities Center, 1981-1988 (Box 21, Folder 165)
  - YMCA of Greater New York (Renewal), 1983-1987 (Box 21, Folder 166)
  - YMCA of Greater New York - Korean Immigrants, 1978-1983 (Box 22, Folder 167)
  - YWCA, 1967-1986 (Box 22, Folder 168)
  - YWCA, National Board of, 1981-1983 (Box 22, Folder 169)
- Project Files, 1966-1999; 3
  - Academia Sinica - Taiwan History, 1986-1992 (Box 22, Folder 170)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1985-1991 (Box 22, Folder 171)
  - Academy of American Poets - Asia and Asian-American Literature Symposium, 1991-1994 (Box 34, Folder 255)
  - Affiliate Artists Inc. - American Russian Youth Orchestra 1993 Tour, 1990-1996 (Box 34, Folder 256)
  - AFS International, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 172)
  - AFS International/Intercultural Programs (Renewal), 1982-1991 (Box 34, Folder 257)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Rise of Industrial East Asia, 1988-1993 (Box 34, Folder 258)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Year 2000, 1968-1973 (Box 82, Folder 609)
  - American Academy of Religion, 1983-1988 (Box 22, Folder 173)
  - American Academy of Religion - Bridging Support, 1990-1996 (Box 34, Folder 259)
  - American Assembly, 1980-1982 (Box 82, Folder 610)
  - American Association of University Women, 1984-1989 (Box 22, Folder 174)
  - The American Bureau for Medical Advancement in China, Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 22, Folder 175)
  - American Council for the Arts, 1988-1993 (Box 34, Folder 260)
  - American Council for Capital Formation - Center for Policy Research, 1984-1990 (Box 22, Folder 176)
  - American Council for the United Nations University - Presidential Award, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 177)
  - American Council for the United Nations University - Presidential Awards and President's Grant, 1987-1989 (Box 34, Folder 261)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1986-1989 (Box 23, Folder 178)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Academia Sinica, Taiwan, 1979-1981 (Box 81, Folder 611)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Chinese Specialists in Hong Kong, Taiwan, and the United States, 1989-1994 (Box 35, Folder 262)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Joint Committee on Chinese Studies, 1986-1988 (Box 23, Folder 179)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Universities Service Center, 1971-1972 (Box 81, Folder 612)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Welch Study, 1969-1972 (Box 82, Folder 613)
  - American Council on Education, 1987-1994 (Box 35, Folder 263)
  - American Craft Museum - Art, 1989-1993 (Box 35, Folder 264-265)
  - American Craft Museum - Master Artists Series: Beatrice Wood and OttoNatzler, 1990-1996 (Box 35, Folder 266)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1988-1991 (Box 35, Folder 267)
  - American Enterprise Institute/Brookings Institute - New Member Seminar, 1986-1989 (Box 23, Folder 181, Box 35, Folder 268)
  - American Enterprise Institute - Separation of Powers, 1989-1994 (Box 36, Folder 269-270)
  - American Enterprise Institute - Ways and Means Committee Seminar, 1985-1987 (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1985-1992 (Box 36, Folder 271, Box 23, Folder 182)
  - American Historical Association, 1987-1991 (Box 36, Folder 272)
  - American Judicature Society - Judicial Conduct and Ethics, 1987-1994 (Box 36, Folder 273-274)
  - American Judicature Society - Judicial Conduct and Ethics for Non-Lawyer Judges, 1991-1994 (Box 37, Folder 275-276)
  - American Leadership Forum, 1986-1992 (Box 23, Folder 183, Box 37, Folder 277)
  - American Leadership Forum - Essence of Leadership Study, 1990-1993 (Box 37, Folder 278)
  - American Leadership Forum - Print and Distribute Research Report, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Folder 279)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1988-1991 (Box 37, Folder 280)
  - American Museum of Natural History - Underwrite Article in Environmental Publication, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Folder 281)
  - American Museum of Natural History and Environment Defense Fund - Effects of Global Warming, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 282)
  - American Red Cross, 1989-1991 (Box 38, Folder 283)
  - American Russian Youth Orchestra, 1993-1996 (Box 38, Folder 284)
  - American Russian Youth Orchestra - Collaboration with Bard College, 1994-1996 (Box 38, Folder 285)
  - American Society of International Law, 1967-1971 (Box 82, Folder 614)
  - American Society of Church History, 1984-1989 (Box 23, Folder 184)
  - American Soviet Youth Orchestra and Oberlin College - President's Grant: Two Month Worldwide Tour, 1990-1993 (Box 38, Folder 286)
  - American Textbook Council - Survey on Religion in Schoolbooks, 1993-1998 (Box 38, Folder 287)
  - American Theological Library Association Preservation Board - Monograph Preservation, 1987-1989 (Box 38, Folder 288)
  - Amon Carter Museum - 19th Century Photography, 1987-1993 (Box 39, Folder 289)
  - Amon Carter Museum - George Bellows' Retrospective, 1989-1993 (Box 39, Folder 290)
  - Amon Carter Museum - Francis William Edmonds, 1986-1988 (Box 23, Folder 185)
  - Amon Carter Museum - Series of "Dossier" Exhibitions and Publications on T. Cole, M. Heade, T. Eakins, 1991-1997 (Box 39, Folder 291)
  - Andover Newton Theological School - Costas Hispanic and Latin American Ministries, 1989-1992 (Box 39, Folder 292)
  - Apollo Muses, Inc. - Administrative Staff Enhancement, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 293)
  - Appalachian Ministries Educational Resource Center, 1990-1994 (Box 39, Folder 294)
  - The Architectural History Foundation, Inc. - Revolving Fund for America nStudies, 1922-1994 (Box 39, Folder 295)
  - Archives of American Art, 1987-1993 (Box 40, Folder 296)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1988-1992 (Box 40, Folder 298)
  - Asia Foundation, 1982-1990 (Box 23, Folder 186-187, Box 24, Folder 188)
  - Asia Foundation - Strengthening Rule of Law in East Asia, 1991-1996 (Box 40, Folder 299-300)
  - Asia Foundation - Laos and Cambodian Refugee Areas, 1989-1991 (Box 40, Folder 301)
  - Asia Foundation - Law Program in Asia, 1969-1976 (Box 82, Folder 615)
  - Asia Society, 1971-1988 (Box 24, Folder 189-190, Box 82, Folder 616)
  - Asia Society - China Council, 1979-1980 (Box 83, Folder 617)
  - Asia Society - The Court Arts of Indonesia, 1988-1993 (Box 40, Folder 302)
  - Asian Cultural Council, 1985-1988 (Box 24, Folder 191)
  - Asian Cultural Council - Asian Art Fellowships (Renewal), 1990-1995 (Box 40, Folder 303)
  - The Aspen Institute, 1973-1988 (Box 24, Folder 192, Box 83, Folder 618)
  - The Aspen Institute - Indochina Policy Forum, 1989-1994 (Box 41, Folder 304)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 83, Folder 619)
  - Associated Kyoto Program (Carleton College), 1985-1992 (Box 24, Folder 193)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1979-1986 (Box 24, Folder 194, Box 83, Folder 622)
  - Association for Asian Studies - Isolated Sea Scholars in the United States, 1989-1993 (Box 41, Folder 305-306)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1979-1985 (Box 83, Folder 620)
  - Association of American Colleges - Alliance for Leadership, 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 195)
  - Association of American Colleges - Council for Liberal Learning, 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 196)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors - Different Voices: The American Art Museum, 1990-1993 (Box 41, Folder 307)
  - Association of Governing Boards Higher Education Issues Panel, 1988-1995 (Box 41, Folder 308-310)
  - Association of Theological Schools - Van Antwerp, 1969-1974 (Box 83, Folder 621)
  - Association of Theological Schools - World Conference, 1989-1993 (Box 42, Folder 311)
  - The Atlantic Council, 1979-1981 (Box 83, Folder 623)
  - The Atlantic Council of the United States National Committee on US-China Relations - Project to Reassess US-China Relations, 1991-1993 (Box 42, Folder 312)
  - Australian National University - Pacific Trade and Development Conference Secretariat, 1987-1990 (Box 42, Folder 313)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1989-1995 (Box 42, Folder 314-315)
  - A Better Chance, Inc., 1979-1995 (Box 43, Folder 316, Box 81, Folder 607)
  - A Better Chance Inc. - Independent Schools Talent Search, 1969-1973 (Box 81, Folder 608)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art - Looking South Art, 1988-1990 (Box 43, Folder 317)
  - Boston Theological Institute - Academic Resources Fund, 1969-1973 (Box 83, Folder 624)
  - Boston Theological Institute - Cross Registration, 1968-1969 (Box 83, Folder 625)
  - Boston University, 1990-1992 (Box 43, Folder 318)
  - Boston University School of Theology - Buddhist-Christian Dialogue Conference, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 319)
  - Bowdoin College, 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 197)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1980-1983 (Box 84, Folder 626)
  - The Boys' Club of New York, 1987-1992 (Box 43, Folder 320)
  - The Boys' Club of New York - Flushing Clubhouse, 1988-1992 (Box 43, Folder 321)
  - Boy's Harbor, Inc., 1989-1994 (Box 43, Folder 322)
  - Brandeis University, 1979-1983 (Box 84, Folder 627)
  - Brick Market Foundation, Inc. - Restoration, 1992-1993 (Box 44, Folder 323-324)
  - The Bridge to China Foundation, 1990-1992 (Box 44, Folder 325)
  - Broad Jump - Prep for Prep (Renewal), 1986-1992 (Box 25, Folder 198)
  - Broad Jump - The Society School, 1971-1972 (Box 84, Folder 628)
  - Broad Jump - Summer Evaluations, 1967-1970 (Box 84, Folder 629)
  - The Brookings Institution, 1980-1985 (Box 25, Folder 199, Box 84, Folder 630)
  - The Brookings Institution - China's US-China Research, 1987-1992 (Box 44, Folder 326-327)
  - Brooklyn Museum of Art - Albert Bierstadt, 1987-1989 (Box 44, Folder 328)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music, 1982-1992 (Box 26, Folder 200, Box 45, Folder 329-330)
  - Brown University - John Carter Brown Library, 1989-1994 (Box 45, Folder 331)
  - Brown University - Leadership Program, 1988-1992 (Box 45, Folder 332)
  - Buffalo Bill Historic Center - Arts, 1986-1997 (Box 45, Folder 333)
  - Caramoor Center for Music and the Arts - Pilot Education Program: Chairman's Award, 1991-1996 (Box 45, Folder 334)
  - Carnegie Council on Ethics and International Affairs, 1984-1993 (Box 26, Folder 201-202)
  - Carnegie Museum of Art - Andy Warhol Archive, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 335)
  - Carnegie Museum of Art - Andy Warhol Archive (Renewal), 1992-1996 (Box 46, Folder 336)
  - The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1988-1991 (Box 46, Folder 337)
  - Center for Responsive Politics, 1987-1989 (Box 46, Folder 338-339)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies - China and Southeast Asia in the Nineties, 1989-1996 (Box 46, Folder 340-341)
  - Center for the Arts, Religion, and Education - Conference on Church and Visual Arts, 1993-1995 (Box 47, Folder 342)
  - Center of Theological Inquiry, 1982-1989 (Box 26, Folder 203-205)
  - Center of Theological Inquiry - Debt Repayment to Princeton Theological Seminary, 1992-1995 (Box 47, Folder 343)
  - Center of Theological Inquiry - Theological Dialogue: Orthodox and Reformed Churches, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 344)
  - Children to Children, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 206)
  - The Children's Aid Society - Community Leaders Development Program, 1990-1997 (Box 47, Folder 345)
  - China Institute (Renewal), 1987-1990 (Box 47, Folder 346)
  - China Institute in America, 1984-1987 (Box 27, Folder 207)
  - China Institute in America - Program Support, 1990-1992 (Box 47, Folder 347)